A Guide to the George K. Strode papers FA104
Rockefeller Archive Center
George K. Strode papers
1910-1965
Rockefeller Archive Center
Strode, George K. (1886-1958)
FA104
1.55 Cubic Feet 6 containers
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
This small collection consists of a selection of personal and professional materials, as well as photographs and audiovisual materials.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated to the RAC by Milton S. Davis in 1984.
Photographs
- Personal Affairs, 1910-1965; 1
  - Diary, 1910-1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Diary, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lions Club, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Clippings, 1957-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings, December 12, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Estates - George K. Strode and Josephine Strode, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Strode Family Geneaology (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Family papers (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - U.S. Army Service, 1919; 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Professional Activities, 1920-1951; 2
  - Awards and Certificates, 1935-1953 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1920-1950 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Retirement, 1950-1951 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Awards, 1919-1953 (Box 1, Folder 13-14, Box 2, Folder 15-23, Box 3, Folder 24-27, Box 4)
- George K. Strode photographs, 1074
  - Miscellaneous - Loose Photographs (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Africa, villages, Field Laboratories
  - Retirement Calendar (Box 2)
    retirement, gifts
  - Strode Family Album (Box A)
    Strode Family, Recreation, Portraits, Group Portraits, Patients, Friends
  - Rockefeller Foundation Album (Box A)
    India, Egypt, Africa, Cities, People, Occupations, Landscapes, Villages, Group Portraits